From the 2024.1 version, we have optimized the extension tool.
Now, in the case of the entire board left and right symmetrical and linked, the operation of the extension board is realized.
Now, through this video, let's learn in detail how to use the extension tool.
In the extension tool storage in the 2D tool bar, you can see that there are two extension tools here.
The extension board slice point and the extension board slice line.
Let's first look at the optimized extension tool.
Click on the extension board slice line.
The tool will switch to the extension board slice line.
You can see the icon and text prompt of the tool in the light bar.
Click on the starting and end points of section 1 that need to be extended.
Now we want to use the tool to extend the front and bottom.
So, we use the extension as section 1.
Click on the starting and end points.
Complete the selection of section 1.
The text prompt of the time icon has been changed.
Click on the starting and end points of section 2 that need to be extended.
The bottom line as section 2.
Select the starting and end points.
Complete the selection of section 2.
Click on the extension board slice window.
You can enter the total length value of the bottom and section 2 according to the design requirements.
You can also enter the distance value that needs to be moved.
You can also enter the negative value to shorten the bottom.
All can be previewed in the 2D window.
After entering the value, click OK.
The extension is completed in the front.
Next, let's see how to use another extension tool, the extension board slice point.
Extend the bottom of the back piece.
Long press the extension board slice line.
Click on the extension board slice point.
The tool will switch to the extension board slice point.
You can see the icon and text prompt of the tool on the light bar.
Click on the line and draw the baseline.
Now we want to use the extension board slice bottom of the back piece of the tool.
You can use the side view point of the back piece as the starting point.
The arrow pointing downwards appears.
You can press the Shift key.
Draw a vertical baseline line according to the instruction line.
The extension position at the bottom as the end point.
Click again.
Complete the baseline line.
The light bar rotates clockwise to one side.
The plate on this side of the baseline line will be extended with the side view point as the center.
You can also shorten the bottom.
There will be a text prompt on the light bar.
Press the D key to maintain the frequency when rotating.
So we can press the D key when operating.
Maintain the bottom frequency.
In the process of extension.
The right click button will play the extension dialogue.
You can enter the length of the plate to be extended.
Or enter the angle of the extension.
After entering, click OK.
So the back piece is completed.
The above is the introduction of the extension tool.
I hope this function.
Can make you more efficient in completing the plate extension.